Anthony Rodriguez-Ortiz

aerodriguezortiz@uchicago.edu | (214) 405-9152 | https://github.com/anthonyero

Professional Summary:

I am a Research Data Analyst Associate at Northwestern University's Feinberg School of Medicine; I provide analytic support to our research projects specializing in social network theory that use our internally developed software suite Network Canvas and I collaborate with external organizational partners providing evaluation services and reports. I am enrolled in a 24-week Coding boot camp offered through Northwestern University that focuses on a MERN full-stack for web development. I am interested in utilizing data-informed methodologies to develop web applications and services and believe my experience offers insight into developing data pipelines.

Education:

Northwestern University School of Professional Studies

Certificate from the Northwestern Coding Boot Camp, expected completion June 2024

Technologies: JavaScript, Node.js, Express.js, PostgreSQL, Mongoose and MongoDB, React.js, HTML, CSS **Projects Include:** A web service to facilitate communication routes between employees and managers to resolve write-ups/infractions ("Event Tracker"), a back-end framework for an e-commerce site using Express.js and PostgreSQL/Sequelize, a social network API utilizing Express.js and MongoDB/Mongoose

University of Chicago, Chicago, IL

Bachelor of Arts in Public Policy Studies with general honors, June 2019

Honors Include: Milgrom Education Impact Fellow, Benjamin A. Gilman International Scholarship Recipient **Relevant Coursework:** Application of Hierarchical Linear Models; Applied Regression Analysis; Statistical Models and Methods; Quantitative Methods in Public Policy; Mathematical Methods for Social Sciences

Professional Experience:

ISGMH at Northwestern University's Feinberg School of Medicine

Chicago, IL

Research Data Analyst Associate

November 2020 – Present

- Assist in the development, documentation, and implementation of network-level survey instruments for projects in the United States and abroad; assist with data management, analysis, and visualizations
- Provide support for peer-reviewed manuscripts and dissemination; I am currently leading two manuscripts
- Co-lead our team's Policy Corp providing policy education at the intersection of our public health projects

Ci3 at the University of Chicago

Chicago, IL

Research Assistant / Kimpton Fellow

July 2019 – July 2020

- Assisted in the development, deployment, recruitment, analysis, and reporting of a statewide initiative to assess healthcare provider needs with the intention of improving contraceptive care
- Co-facilitated our organization's Youth Advisory Council which provides valuable insight into our projects by prototyping materials/instruments and receiving feedback
- Conducted both quantitative and qualitative data analysis, developed visuals for reporting, provided background literature reviews, and supplied administrative support and outreach for various projects

The Milgrom Education Impact Fellowship

Chicago, IL

Milgrom Education Impact Fellow

June 2018 – September 2018

- Established framework for program evaluation and designed surveys to determine fellowship curriculum for my summer cohort
- Conducted both quantitative and qualitative analysis of past year's cohort survey results regarding their fellowship experiences to present to Milgrom Fellowship funders and helped analyze my own summer cohort's data
- Taught about fifty-five students visual arts, photography, and robotics as part of a summer enrichment program for elementary and middle school children on the South Side of Chicago

Skills:

Web Development: JavaScript, Node.js, Express.js, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, React.js, Render, Git Data Analysis: R, RMarkdown, Network Canvas Suite, Python, Tableau, Gephi, HLM Software, SPSS, STATA Languages: Fluent in Spanish